# **Emmanuel Imolorhe**

Experienced Front End developer focused on web apps, with excellent interpersonal skills, having the ability to grow positive relationships with people of diverse backgrounds. Proven adaptability to learn new systems, work with and support others in a team effort while working within a fast-paced environment.

Lagos, Nigeria +234 809-943-1100 imolorhe@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/eioluseyi

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Crescat AS**, Norway — Frontend Web Developer

OCTOBER 2022 - PRESENT

- Collaborated with team members to develop an event management system, which serves a huge customer base.
  Currently over a milestone of 25 thousand events created.
  Frontend technologies such as VueJs and Tailwind were used
- Played a key role in migrating the legacy system from Vue 2 to Vue 3, with TypeScript support
- Developed functional user interfaces (UI) for application functionalities in accordance with design guidelines
- Developed UI design solutions for impromptu additions to the application's functionalities
- Crafted optimized logic to maintain the quality of the application's UX
- Worked along with coworkers to keep the team's progress coordinated

### **HabariPay**, Lagos — Frontend Web Developer

APRIL 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2022

- Contributed majorly to the frontend development of a payment gateway system serving a large customer base using frontend technologies such as ReactJs and NextJs
- Built responsive UI layouts for new features on the application, based on design specifications
- Wrote optimized logic that preserves the quality of the UX of the application
- Came up with UI design alternatives for new ad-hoc features on the application
- Developed an interactive, functional and visually appealing website and blog for the effective marketing of the product, using NextJs and Wordpress respectively.
- Collaborated with team mates to ensure progress stays in sync

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript · React.js · Vue.js Next.js · Nuxt.js · SSR ES6 · Webpack · HTML CSS · Bootstrap · Tailwind GraphQL · Rest API · Git

#### **LANGUAGES**

English

## **Zhaptek Enterprises**, Lagos — Frontend Web Developer

JANUARY 2018 - JANUARY 2021

- Handled the frontend development of web apps for Zhaptek clients primarily using VueJs, HTML & CSS
- Converted UI designs into fully functioning features, following the documented specifications
- Developed a Point of Sale solution which is offline-first and has real-time synchronization to the cloud, used for operations in neighborhood stores in remote areas.
- Was responsible for the quality of the client web applications handled by Zhaptek
- Contributed to the design of new Zhaptek client product ideas, technology choices and architecture
- Brainstormed with the Zhaptek design team to improve existing designs for functionality and accessibility

## **Syscomptech**, Lagos — Frontend Web Developer

MARCH 2017 - JANUARY 2018

- Built some finance based web apps for Syscomptech clients using Php based technologies
- Refactored some existing applications for logistics booking and management
- Built and maintained websites for Syscomptech businesses using Wordpress and other technologies
- Improved quality of existing websites; in design and performance
- Maintained the primary Syscomptech website

#### **EDUCATION**

## National Youth Service Corps — NYSC

2017 JAN - 2017 DEC

State posted: Lagos

PPA: Sycomptech Communications

Callup number: 338889

Certificate number: A003551571

**Covenant University,** Nigeria — BSc. Industrial Physics – Renewable Energy

2012 - 2016